Ömer Buğra Yıldırım

bugrayldrm@gmail.com • 05324180840 • GitHub

Backend Developer

Greetings, I'm a mechanical engineering graduate with a IT audit background looking for a career change towards application development. I've graduated from Bogazici University 3 years ago and been working ever since. Always was into coding from a young age. I consider myself determined and a little stubborn as a consequence.

Specialties: Python, C#, C++, Django Rest, Tensorflow, Unreal Engine 4, Unity

Technologies: Tensorflow, Numpy, Matplotlib

Languages: English: Advanced

Programming resources used for self-learning: Udacity Advanced AI Nanodegree garduate, reuven

m. lerner, talk python, stack overflow, pybites, gamedev.tv, datacamp

Interests: Guitar, gaming

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Turkcell, İstanbul Sept 2019 - July 2021

IT auditor

Performing audits of IT systems according to the audit schedule.

Anel Group, İstanbul

July 2018 - Sept 2020

Project Planning Engineer

Project management and planning in MEP(mechanical-electrical) projects such as Abu Dhabi Airport, UCL Proton Therapy Hospital etc. .

EDUCATION AND COURSES

Mechanical Engineering (Bachelor's Degree), Boğaziçi

2012 - 2018

Üniversitesi

Patika Patika Plentific Django Bootcamp **Udacity** Advanced AI Nanodegree *Link*

November 2021- January 2022

March 2020- June 2020

PROJECTS

Django bootcamp project (Code/Live)

2021

Technologies: Python, Django Rest Framework

Features: This project is an e-commerce web application backend that uses django and postgresql

Building escape 2020

Technologies: C++, Unreal Engine 4

Features: Small game concept developed with ue4

Other projects on My GitHub Profile.

Linked-in Link